<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stat Ed on Adam Loy</title>
    <link>/tags/stat-ed/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Stat Ed on Adam Loy</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 Adam Loy</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/stat-ed/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Inferece for the Classroom</title>
      <link>/project/classroom-viz-inf/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/classroom-viz-inf/</guid>
      <description>In the classroom, we traditionally visualize inferential concepts related to inference using static graphics or interactive apps. For example, there is a long history of using apps to visualize sampling distributions. Recent developments in statistical graphics have created an opportunity to bring additional visualizations into the classroom to hone student understanding. Specifically, the lineup protocol (Buja et al. 2009) provides a framework for students see the difference between signal and noise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data Science for Statistics</title>
      <link>/project/ds4stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ds4stats/</guid>
      <description>Shonda Kuiper, Laura Chihara and I developed a series of tutorials and case studies that can be used in a variety of courses to introduce data-scientific concepts. You can find these materials on Github.
This work was funded by grants from the Associated Colleges of the Midwest and the Teagle Foundation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sampling Variability and the G.O.P. Debate</title>
      <link>/post/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/post/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>The Upshot featured a nice article on the role of sampling variability in the selection of the 10 candidates invited to the first GOP debate. The post includes a nice visualization of simulated possible participants, assuming that basic polling data are “true”.
Students in an introductory statistics course, especially one using a simulation-based curriculum, would benefit from reading this story. The article is a great spring board for talking about simulation and sampling variability, and also illustrates that these topics are relevant!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>